# Oluwakayode Adediran

Nigeria • +2347043610278 • stephenkayade@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/stephen-adediran • https://uridevmedia.vercel.app

### **Frontend Engineer**

Highly motivated software engineer (Frontend) with more than 4 years of work experience in Edtech, Ecommerce, Fintech, and even government bodies. In my professional practice in software development, I have focused on innovation, self-improvement, and delivering valuable software that can enhance the achievement of organizational goals. While I have a solid grip on frontend development, I have also started enhancing my skills by learning Javascript for backend development with Node.js, with a good basic knowledge of different programming languages and frameworks, I am well-equipped to keep creating values for innovative and progressive teams.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### Inosuft Technologies • Ogbomoso, Nigeria Frontend Developer

09/2022 - Present

- Led the effort in frontend implementation in some in-house multiple enterprise-level microservice applications in the Fintech and EdTech space using the latest technologies of Reactjs, Typescript, ContextAPI, and Bootstrap.
- Designed and implemented scalable applications and integrated with APIs built using the microservices architecture using Nodejs.
- Worked as the main frontend engineer in the implementation of the learning platform and admin portal of Concreap.
- Worked as the main frontend engineer in the implementation of vacepay website, admin and corporate portals.
- Worked as the main frontend engineer in the implementation of Terraswitch website, admin, and corporate portals
- collaborated with UI/UX designers and backend engineers to implement and integrate frontend applications for both in-house and client based projects.
- Continuously Implementing new features as required per project.

# Cephas ICT HUB • Ogbomoso, Nigeria Frontend Developer, Instructor

07/2020 - 05/2024

- Worked as lead frontend engineer on SDG Grants portal a portal that helped in the collection and screening of hundreds of applications from Lagos state residents for a grant worth ₦255 million for the funding of 51 projects in the state.
- Worked as the main frontend engineer in the implementation of Cebiz a payroll patfom for organization (still in development).
- Facilitated over 1200 hours of web development classes both online and physical classes.

#### **SKILLS**

Bitbucket, Bootstrap, ContextAPI, CSS3, ExpressJs, Frontend, Git, Github, Heroku, HTML5, JavaScript, JIRA, Machine Learning, MongoDb, NodeJs, Npm, Postman, Railway, React, Reactquery, Redux, Swagger, TailwindCSS, Tanstack query, TypeScript, Vercel, I enjoy learning during free times, I enjoy listening to music

#### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Technology in Pure and Applied Mathematics

Ladoke Akintola University of Technology Ogbomoso, Oyo

- Trained 200+ students on web development.
- collaborated with UI/UX designers and backend engineers to implement and integrate frontend applications for both in-house and client based projects.
- Worked with departments across the company including marketing, project management, and admin in developing new ideas, initiatives, products, and services.

### Concreap • Ogbomoso, Nigeria

09/2022 - 11/2023

### **Frontend Developer**

- Worked as the main frontend engineer on the second version of the website.
- Worked closely with the UI/UX designers and backend engineers to implement and integrate frontend for robust dashboards for the Edtech platform.
- · Responsible for testing of frontend applications.
- worked closely with UI/UX designers and backend engineers to implement and integrate frontend applications.

## Rubies Tech • Lagos, Nigeria

04/2023 - 08/2023

### Frontend Engineer • Part-time

- Responsible for mentoring 4 interns in frontend development.
- Help developers improve their communication skills, teamwork, time management, and other soft skills essential for a successful career in frontend engineering.
- Responsible for planning and developing a curriculum for interns or students.
- Assisted interns in troubleshooting technical issues, debugging code, and finding effective solutions to challenges encountered during frontend development projects
- led the effort in revamping the organisation's website by the interns.
- Offered one-on-one mentoring sessions to discuss career goals, skills development, and provide personalised guidance on how to achieve them.
- Provide regular feedback on mentees' performance, progress, and areas for improvement. Participate in performance evaluations and contribute insights to help inform career development plans

# Schoolshell Limited • FCT Abuja, Nigeria

10/2021 - 08/2022

## Frontend Developer

- Redesigned and integrated Student's result page on the mobile application driving effective usage of the mobile application using React Native, and ContextAPI.
- Improved the overall Interface of the mobile application.
- Worked closely with the team lead in fixing issues noticed on the app.

### Edves Nigeria Limited • Lagos, Nigeria

06/2019 - 09/2019

### Machine Learning, Web Development, Internship

• Responsible for analysis the company's data to gain insights

- Responsible for collection of data using data mining techniques to further gain insight on the existing platform which in-turn improve decision making on products that are in pipeline.
- Learned the building blocks of web development which includes HTML5 and CSS3.
- worked closely with the CEO on the proper data mining to be carried out...

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

### Web Design for Web Developers

02/2020

Udemy

### Certificate of Participation in Al Saturdays

Al Saturdays

### **PROJECTS**

Vacepay 09/2023 - 06/2024

Vacepay

Vacepay provides an easy and secure way for online and offlinedigital payments for underserved SMBs and solo entrepreneurs in Africa.

visit https://vacepay.com

Terraswitch 03/2024 - 06/2024

**Terraswitching** 

Terraswitch is building the payment infrastructure for Africa. that enable payment processing needs using the most secure, user friendly and emerging technologies.

https://terraswitching.com

### Concreap website

06/2023 - 07/2023

Concreap

Conreap takes a non-traditional approach in building smart and innovative tech talents.

visit https://concreap.com

Inosuft website 10/2022 - 10/2022

**Inosuft Technologies** 

Inosuft is a strategic technology company crafting & innovating valuable digital solutions to help businesses grow

visit https://inosuft.com

### **SDG GRANT PORTAL**

10/2021 - 05/2022

Built a grants platform that included 3 dashboards that helped in the collection and screening of hundreds of applications from Lagos state residents for a grant worth \(\frac{\text{\text{\text{\text{Pot}}}}{255}\) million for the funding of 51 projects in the state. Check the SDG Grant Portal.

visit https://grants.lsvc.ng/

**TARM** website

10/2020 - 12/2020

**TARM Nigeria** 

TARM is a Christian body that exists to raise true ambassadors of Christ who are firebrands in their areas of influence

visit https://tarminternational.org

### **VOLUNTEERING & LEADERSHIP**

### AlSaturday16 Lautech

11/2019 - 08/2020

Mentor | Instructor • Ogbomoso, Oyo

An AI community in my undergrad school where the nextGen AI engineers are groomed, I volunteered to mentor a team that included 5 members on a machine learning project Hotel Bookings dataset was obtained from Zindi africa